

Sohyeon Jeon

Seoul, Korea

Phone

+82 10 - 4403 - 9233

Email

sohyeonclaire@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shj021/

Website

https://soooj.github.io/sh/web.html

Git

https://github.com/ssoooj/shjproject.git

Skills

Python

Matlab

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

SOL

Git

Linux

Database

Computer Networking

Microsoft Office

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Profile

I'm a passionate researcher in Cognitive Science and Artificial Intelligence. Full of curiosity and positive energy all the time, I find problem-solving with code intriguing and fun. My ability to learn everything quickly makes it easier for me to blend in on new environments and new tasks. Experiences in fMRI, EEG, Virtual Reality targeting humans, data analysis, and image processing helped me widen my perspective in terms of methodology. I learned data structure, algorithms, and programming by myself.

Employment History

Researcher, Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST), Seoul

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

- Develop a supervised and semi-supervised algorithm for annotating brain regions and building an atlas
- Web-based brain image analysis software development
- Deep learning method for large-scale brain image data analysis

Samsung Int'l Hotel Management Agent, The Shilla Hotels & Resorts, Seoul

OCTOBER 2013 - APRIL 2014

- Management in contracts of hotels in the U.S. (New York, New Jersey)
- Business trip arrangement for the executives in Samsung Group

Education

M.Sc. in Cognitive Science, Seoul National University, Seoul

MARCH 2017 - AUGUST 2019

Title: An Event-Related fMRI Study of Bilingual Lexical Processing and Cross-linguistic Interaction

B.A. in Philosophy, Kyunghee University, Seoul

MARCH 2013 - FEBRUARY 2017

Experience

Research Assistant, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Performed a neurocognitive experiment for patients with dementia
- Assisted in human experiments and analyzed acquired data

Research Assistant, Seoul National University, Seoul

JUNE 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

- Conducted a neurolinguistic behavioral experiment and analyzed acquired data
- Performed a spatial orientation experiment for human subjects using Virtual Reality
- Assisted in the development of research protocols and procedures

Research Assistant, Seoul National University, Seoul

MARCH 2017 - MAY 2017

- Worked on the project investigating the perceptual ability of bilingual children using ${\tt EEG}$
- Assisted and performed experiments in the lab

Languages

English

Korean

Japanese

Activities

Poster Presenter, Brain Science Institute Poster Presentation, Seoul

DECEMBER 2020

Title: Building Digital Brain Atlas from Scratch

Poster Presenter, Brain Science Institute Symposium, Gwangju

DECEMBER 2019

Title: Annotating Brain with Atlas

Poster Presenter, International Brain Research Organization (IBRO), Daegu

SEPTEMBER 2019

Title: Bilingual lexical processing and cross-linguistic interaction: A behavioral and fMRI Study

Research Performance

Participating Projects

Next generation multiscale functional connectomics, KIST

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

Comprehensive structural mapping & a integrative DB construction of basal ganglia circuits related to neurological disorders, KIST

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

Integrated structural and functional mapping of neural circuits using the Smart-AR microscope, KIST

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2021

Multisensory interaction for perceptual categorization and spatial orientation,

Seoul National University

SEPTEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Neural mechanisms and interaction of motor efference copy and sensory feedback,

Seoul National University

SEPTEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Research Papers

Kim, A., Chang, M., Choi, Y., Jeon, S., & Lee, K. (2018). The Effect of Immersion on Emotional Responses to Film Viewing in a Virtual Environment. 2018 IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (VR). doi: 10.1109/vr.2018.8446046

Currently, papers for primate brain research are in process

Research Interests

Artificial Intelligence & Deep Learning
Predictive modeling and pattern recognition
Data Science
Topological Data Analysis

Computational Neuroscience